Iehedi Hasan

J (+880)196-950-0278

■ mhasan912@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/moidda

https://github.com/Moidda

RESEARCH INTEREST

I am a **Software Engineer** specializing in Research at Chaldal. Outside of work, I am involved in academic research. My primary area of interest is Human Computer Interaction. I'm also passionate about Visualization, VR/AR, and Ubiquitous technologies. Through my work experience, I've gained expertise and interest in **Algorithms** and **Systems**, including Networking, Distributed Systems and System Design.

EDUCATION

BSc in Computer Science and Engineering

May 2023

Bangladesh University of Engineering and Technology (BUET), Dhaka, Bangladesh

Notable Courses:

CSE 305 - Computer Architecture CSE 309 - Compiler

CSE 321 - Computer Networks CSE 463 - Introduction to Bioinformatics

CSE 409 - Computer Graphics CSE 471 - Machine Learning CSE 461 - Algorithm Engineering MATH 247 - Linear Algebra

CSE 313 - Operating System MATH 145 - Calculus and Coordinate Geometry CSE 405 - Computer Security HUM 477 - Sociology for Science and Technology

PUBLICATIONS

- Mubassira, T., Hasan, M., Sharmin, S. (2024). "Reading the Mind's Eye: Detecting Trauma-Vulnerability in Individuals by Analyzing Attention Through Eye-Tracking". In: Zaslavsky, A., Ning, Z., Kalogeraki, V., Georgakopoulos, D., Chrysanthis, P.K. (eds) Mobile and Ubiquitous Systems: Computing, Networking and Services. MobiQuitous 2023 (EAI Mobiguitous 2023). DOI: 10.1007/978-3-031-63992-0_28
- Mubassira, T., Hasan, M., Mukta, J., Islam, A (2024). "Enhancing EmoBot: An In-Depth Analysis of User Expectation and Satisfaction in An Emotion-Aware Chatbot". In: International Conference on Networking, Systems and Security, 2024. (Peer Reviewed)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Towards perceiving and resolving the impediments to reporting for the developing countries

Human Computer Interaction, Generic Reporting System

Aug 2024 - Current

- DOI: 10.1109/NSYSS2.2017.8267790
- Live At: ureporter.cse.buet.ac.bd
- Supervisor: Dr. A. B. M. Alim Al Islam, Professor, CSE, BUET
- Collaboration: With Tarik Reza Toha, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill
- **Contribution:** Improved the system in collaboration with the research team

Detecting Sentiment in Anonymous Submissions: A Study on User Report Data

Human Computer Analysis, Sentiment Analysis

Sep 2024 - Current

- Supervisor: Dr. A. B. M. Alim Al Islam, Professor, CSE, BUET
- Contribution: Performed sentiment analysis on crowd sourced anonymous reports

Fine-Tuning GPT-2 for Bengali Auto Text Completion Using Literary Corpus: A Qualitative Analysis

Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning

Jan 2023 - Mar 2023

- Presentation: Slides
- Supervisor: Dr. Mohammed Eunus Ali, Professor, CSE, BUET
- Contribution: Fine-tuned GPT-2 with a Bengali literature corpus to improve auto text completion

INDUSTRY EXPERIENCE

Chaldal Ltd. June 2023 - Present

R&D

ASAP Delivery

- Designed an algorithm to calculate geographical area overlapping a route, through which a driver can detour for a specific slack time period without impacting other deliveries in the route

- Impact: Grocery delivery within 20 to 40 minutes in Dhaka

Last Mile Routing Algorithm

- Designed a new **routing algorithm** using different heuristic and probabilistic search methods
- **Impact:** Increased on-time delivery by 15%

Traffic Estimate

- Developed a timeseries database and supervised an interpolation project using spatio-temporal models to fill missing traffic speed data.
- Impact: Improved estimates for Dhaka roads by 53.53% for cycles, 28.83% for motorbikes, and 28.73% for vans

Automate Task Assignment

- Designed and deployed an algorithm for solving the task assignment problem via an API endpoint, integrated into a system for periodic task assignment within the warehouse.
- **Impact:** Increased on-time dispatch by 16%

System Design

Micro-services communication

- Designed and implemented a **gRPC-based communication system** across three services to transmit information at specific events, tested it in a QA environment, and oversaw its system-wide deployment.
- **Impact:** Decreased driver idle time by 7 minutes

Spatial Database Model

- Developed a **spatial database model** which can store polygonal area and query with intersecting geolocation
- Impact: Enhanced vehicle utilization by restricting certain vehicle types in specific areas

Re-Modeling Task Assignment system

- Designed a more efficient task assignment model, refactored existing models, redesigned the UI, and improved underlying logic.
- Impact: Increased picker's efficiency by 1.2x

ACHIEVEMENTS

- 5th/50 teams Code Samurai Hackathon 2022
- $-8^{th}/86$ teams BUET CSE FEST IUPC 2019
- $-10^{th}/84$ teams DUET IUPC 2019
- 13th/59 teams National Programming Contest
- Hackerrank: Problem Solving (Intermediate)
- Codeforces Max Rating: Expert (1871)

SELECTED PROJECTS

Trapped (Game)

Unity Game Engine, C#

Developed a 2D action and puzzle platformer

P5js-Raycasting

Javascript, HTML

Implemented raycasting using p5-is library for visualization

xv6 Memory Management (OS)

Linux, C, bash, kernel programming

Enhanced the xv6 operating system by adding support for memory management.

Simple C Compiler

C, YACC, Bison

Developed a C compiler capable of reading small C programs and generating corresponding machine code for execution.

CNN from Scratch

Python

A simple implementation of a convolutional neural network using Python and NumPy, trained on the NumtaDB dataset to recognize Bengali digits.

Chaldaal (Web App)

django/python, oracle/sql, HTML/CSS, JS

Created an online grocery shop similar to chaldal.com

Smart Construction Work System (Web App)

Django, SQLite, HTML/CSS, JS

Developed a citywide smart construction management system